<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>Javascript on kevinkivi.com</title><link>https://kevinkivi.com/tags/javascript/</link><description>Recent content in Javascript on kevinkivi.com</description><generator>Hugo -- 0.148.1</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 16 Jul 2025 10:44:00 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://kevinkivi.com/tags/javascript/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Developing for Old Browsers</title><link>https://kevinkivi.com/posts/developing-for-old-browsers/</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 Jul 2025 10:44:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://kevinkivi.com/posts/developing-for-old-browsers/</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="this-post-is-still-a-draft-come-back-later">This post is still a draft. Come back later.&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>I have a Windows 98 SE virtual machine that I like to tinker with. I have Apache and PHP 5.1.X running on it. I have ansi.sys enabled MS-DOS terminal&lt;sup id="fnref:1">&lt;a href="#fn:1" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">1&lt;/a>&lt;/sup>, so I can have colors and create cool CLI apps&lt;sup id="fnref:2">&lt;a href="#fn:2" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">2&lt;/a>&lt;/sup>. I have VIM 7.3 installed in it.&lt;sup id="fnref:3">&lt;a href="#fn:3" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">3&lt;/a>&lt;/sup> Surprisingly enough vim-plug and vim-airline work.&lt;sup id="fnref:4">&lt;a href="#fn:4" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">4&lt;/a>&lt;/sup>&lt;sup id="fnref:5">&lt;a href="#fn:5" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">5&lt;/a>&lt;/sup> This means we can have a very modern development expierience on Vim. Vim 7.3 has omni-completion (a type of intellisense) and JS syntax highlighting. For editing text files or keeping notes I also have Notepad++. &lt;sup id="fnref:6">&lt;a href="#fn:6" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">6&lt;/a>&lt;/sup> I also have webone installed. So I can connect to https sites. webone is a proxy that runs in a docker container that terminates the TLS connection. &lt;sup id="fnref:7">&lt;a href="#fn:7" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">7&lt;/a>&lt;/sup>
As a fun exercise for myself I wanted to create a modern web app that would work on an old browser. I first picked IE5. Because it is the first browser to support XmlHttpRequest, which means it could be used to run a &amp;ldquo;modern&amp;rdquo; web app. I then upgraded my IE5 to IE5.5. Now I&amp;rsquo;m thinking of compromising and running IE6. I have created a bundler and a JSX transpiler and a watcher. I have created a react-like web application, that supports routing and state. It supports JSX. Immediately if it detects a file change it compiles and bundles the files. And I just need to hit refresh on the browser and I can view my changes. Currently I don&amp;rsquo;t know if all of this works on my Windows 98 yet. It should though. I don&amp;rsquo;t like develeping on my Win98 because it doesn&amp;rsquo;t have git. So I can keep my files in sync nice. That is why I&amp;rsquo;m creating a git &amp;ldquo;client&amp;rdquo; for Windows 98. It wont work completely standalone. It actually needs a server. Because it is a thin-client.
Internet Explorer &amp;lt;=6 had interesting quirks.[^doublemargin]&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Damerau-Levenshtein in the browser or: How I almost lost my mind!</title><link>https://kevinkivi.com/posts/real-damerau-levenshtein/</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 Feb 2025 13:50:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://kevinkivi.com/posts/real-damerau-levenshtein/</guid><description>&lt;p>Call me lazy, but when I&amp;rsquo;m prototyping something. I want to just be able to &lt;code>&amp;lt;script src=&amp;quot;&lt;/code> a library quickly. I don&amp;rsquo;t want to &lt;code>npm&lt;/code>, &lt;code>webpack&lt;/code> or any such nonsense, if I&amp;rsquo;m just quickly winging it. Now most of the time it&amp;rsquo;s wonderful, I can just find a url from jsdelivr or some other CDN that has been minified and ready to be sourced. But sometimes you can&amp;rsquo;t. This is one of those times.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Speed Reader App</title><link>https://kevinkivi.com/posts/speed-reader/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Sep 2022 13:57:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://kevinkivi.com/posts/speed-reader/</guid><description>&lt;p>I have been using this great speed reading webapp called Spreeder. It prints out one word at a time to the middle of the screen. It prints them out at 300WPM by default (raising the average reading speed of 200WPM). It is very effective for short bursts at least. Link to Spreeder: &lt;a href="https://www.spreeder.com/app.php?intro=1">https://www.spreeder.com/app.php?intro=1&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I was wondering if I could dev this in one day (more or less). Here is the result: &lt;a href="https://nake89.github.io/speed-reader/">https://nake89.github.io/speed-reader/&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Javascript: Cronometer ratio changer</title><link>https://kevinkivi.com/posts/cronometer-ratio-changer/</link><pubDate>Sat, 21 Jul 2018 09:51:40 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kevinkivi.com/posts/cronometer-ratio-changer/</guid><description>&lt;p>I created a script (with the help of my wife) which can change the ratio of foods. E.g.To make new food in Cronometer such as date paste, export &amp;ldquo;Dates&amp;rdquo; JSON from Cronometer. Then import the file. If the date paste is 15% water and 85% dates, then make the multiplier 0.85 and name it as you want. View at JSFiddle: &lt;a href="https://jsfiddle.net/nake89/2k78jxpt/">https://jsfiddle.net/nake89/2k78jxpt/&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>